The SCOAN Sunday Service
You may be seated, thank you!
- Hallelujah!
- (Amen.)
Emmanuel!
(God with us, Matthew 1:23)
The message that I have for you today is
'The burden in our spirit'.
That is; when one is thinking, worried and troubled
your spirit cannot be free to attract the Spirit of God.
We cannot be available for God when we are worried.
Are you with me?
When you are worried, troubled -
maybe something is troubling or worrying you,
you cannot be available for God's Spirit.
Our spirits are free when we are free.
This is why in 1 Peter 5:7, when you start reading from verse 7,
it says, "Your cares, your troubles - to God because He cares for you and He loves you."
When we are troubled, we cannot be sensitive to the Spirit of God.
You need a free spirit to pray.
You need a free spirit to hear from God.
You need a free spirit to do what?
To hear from God.
You cannot hear from God when your spirit is troubled.
He is the Landlord; He cannot share that apartment with anyone.
When you say someone is the landlord of a house; you pay house rent to the man.
He cannot share...,
He is the landlord, the owner; He doesn't want to share anything.
He created you - spirit, soul and body.
Without this free spirit, you cannot
act upon the Word of God.
You only hear the Word; you cannot do anything about it.
You will only hear, "Jesus is Lord! Jesus is Saviour! Jesus is this, Jesus is that..."
As you hear, it goes this way, when you are troubled.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Spirit of God will be released to the degree you stand in reverence,
in obeying and in honour of His Word.
The Spirit of God will be released.
As you honour the Word, the Spirit increases.
It's like you are being filled.
You know, as you eat food you get filled.
The more you eat you get filled...
You need a free spirit to get along, to act with God.
Without a free spirit , there is nothing, nothing and nothing...
So therefore...
Leave it for God; don't worry yourself.
- Leave it for what?
- (God.)
Open 1 Peter chapter 5.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Chapter 5 verse 7.
"Give all your worries and cares to God for He cares about you."
Listen to that.
Give all your what?
All your worries and cares; cares mean trouble, burden - whatever you call it, it is a foolish thing.
... for He cares for you.
This is why when you want to open you Bible to read, its time to give all your what?
Troubles.
Give all your cares and troubles to God.
That is, leave all - whatever is bothering you, worrying you.
When you don't; you will read and you will not able to obey what you read.
You will read the Bible as if you are reading literature, a book.
You know when you are reading the Bible, you are reading the Holy Spirit
but any other book outside Bible, when you are reading them, you are reading about event.
Some will say, "Is that actually possible to give all worries? How will one just overlook his trouble?
Is it actually possible?"
Yes! That is actually why God gave you discretion.
You can choose to cry, you can choose to laugh.
You can choose to dance, you can choose not to.
You can choose to leave here, walk out of this place and you can choose to sit.
You can choose to stand...
This is why Jesus met this man at the pool of Bethesda.
He said, "What can I do for you?"
He knew the problem the man was facing.
He was so sick that he could not jump into the pool.
He needed someone to help him to jump into the pool.
But Jesus knew his problem but he said still, "What can I do for you?"
He knew that he might have refused him.
He knew he might have disagreed with Him.
He knew that he might have made Him walk away.
"- What can I do for you?
- Yes, I needed someone to carry me to the pool.
... each time the water is stirred - that is turning.
But here I am, so sick, no one to carry me to the pool.
- Can I help?"
He said, "Yes, if you will."
Its not all up to God; certainly, it is not all up to you.
It takes you genuine willingness and God's ability to achieve something.
You can choose to overlook everything and open your Bible and read.
Don't look for the solution of the trouble you have, in the Bible.
Read Bible for the salvation of you soul.
Don't be searching for solution of your problem.
"I am sick. I want to see where Jesus healed the sick person in the Bible";
and you start searching for that - No!
"I am poor, I want to know who was poor like me in the Bible and was revived."
No, the Bible is not for that.
Therefore, when you want to sleep, don't open your Bible because of your trouble.
In the night, when you are about to sleep, you open the Bible to find something against your enemy.
You want to fire your enemy; you open Psalms 35, and you read.
After reading you place it under your pillow.
When your enemy comes, he will wake you up and say, "Come. Carry the thing you put under your pillow."
You will carry it, and he will use the same Bible to flog you.
By the time you wake up you say, " Ah! Does it mean that the bible is not the Word of God?
Why does the enemy use this Word to beat me?"
No. You make Bible work.
Bible itself cannot work; you make the Bible work.
Tell your neighbor, "I make it work".
You make it work.
The Bible itself cannot just work.
You make it work, or not to work.
It's the library of apostles put together.
Hallelujah
Thank you, rise up...
Hallelujah!
Ask for a free spirit.
You know I told you; meditation reveals the burden in our spirit.
Meditation exposes the burden in your spirit, the burden in you, the worry.
This is why we have faith bracelet.
When you meditate, "Take more of me, give me more of You", before you know it, the burden is gone.
You will begin to think of Jesus; then, you can pray.
You find joy, naturally;
it comes naturally,
It comes spontaneously.
Spontaneously - just naturally the joy comes.
Joy is not created by you and I.
It originates with God.
Joy!
"Take more of me; give me more of you..."
By the time you meditate this, that burden - worry is gone;
you would feel joy - a kind of inner joy.
That is the time to pray.
Are you with me?
This is why we call meditation a visit with God.
What is meditation?
Meditation in Gods Word is what?
A visit with God.
Meditation in Gods Word is a visit with God.
Now you are happy.
It does not mean that in coming hours there will be nothing troubling you.
You are a human, since you have flesh.
You will continue to have something troubling you, but you will continue to overcome.
Are you with me?
It is not that you will not have something troubling you in the future - no!
No, it is not in the Bible.
In this world there will be what?
There will be trouble!
"In this world there will be trouble. Cheer up; I have overcome" (John 16:33).
The SCOAN Sunday Service
This is why He said, "I pray your faith will not fail."
If He said, "your faith will not fail", it means there will be trouble that will tempt your faith.
"I pray your faith will not fail"; it means
there will be time our faith will be shaken.
As you continue to live in this world, something will continue to come to threaten your faith.
And that thing helps to grow our relationship.
It is an instrument to grow our relationship.
That is the time you will see the need of God more.
- The need of who?
- (God) - the more.
It strengthens our desire and our determination for God.
It strengthens our what?
Our desire and determination for God.
It makes us to see the need for God.
He has prayed for us that our faith would not fail; that is the prayer He left behind.
He said to His disciple and you are one of them.
He said, "I pray that your faith will not fail".
It means your faith will be tested.
Ask your neighbor what is testing your faith, right now?
Ask you neighbor.
(What is testing your faith, right now?)
Remember, "I pray your faith will not fail".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
That means that what you are going through - God is aware.
It has been prophesied, you will go through them.
But, it will not impair you but improve you.
It has been prophesied by our Lord Jesus Christ, "My disciples, My followers will go through this".
It has been prophesied.
If you are one of the followers, it will not impair you.
But if you are not of the followers, it will impair you.
If you are one of the followers, it will improve you - whatever you go through.
There can be no promotion without test.
There can be no improvement without test.
And what is your test?
What is my test?
What are you going through?
What am I going through?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When it is time to go up, it is time to be tested.
Oh, I'm talking to you.
When it is time to go up, it is time to what?
(To be tested.)
He said, "I pray" - it was a prayer offered for you
This means that whatever you are going through has been prophesied.
- Hallelujah!
- (Amen!)
So, it has been prophesied that this and that will happen.
Some things will be changeable and many will not be changeable.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
It is written.
It gladdens in my heart, anytime I read; when Jesus said...
He is aware of your cares and your trouble.
He says, your cares and worries - leave it to God, because He cares about you,
he is concerned about you.
Jesus loves you just as He loves every apostle.
And every apostle in the Bible, read about them,
everyone had their own what?
Challenges.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
And their challenges strengthened their desire.
The apostles' challenges strengthened their desire.
They paid the supreme price to bring the Gospel you and I enjoy today.
What price have you paid?
I pray your faith will not fail, in Jesus name.
(Amen!)
We believe you have been inspired by the clip you have just watched.
Click here to subscribe, to witness more of God's power at work in our generation today
and stay up-to-date with the latest prophecies, deliverances, sermons and testimonies
from the Synagogue Church Of All Nations.
Emmanuel TV – changing lives, changing nations and changing the world.